Deepak Satapathy () Featured

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Project Management, Data Mining, Data Visualization, System Architecture, Requirement Gathering, Google Analytics, Application Support, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Python, HTML, CSS



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Mphasis Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree:

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Delhi / NCR Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer/Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Project Management, Data

Mining, Data Visualization, System Architecture, Requirement Gathering, Google Analytics, Application

Support, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Python, HTML, CSS

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Summary

Solutions-driven business analyst with experience leading cross-functional teams in the development, documentation and delivery of process innovations driving the attainment of business goals. Seek opportunities to transform company practices into fresh, cost-effective solutions leading to more efficient operations.

Work Experience

Mphasis as Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2020 to Till Date

Provided inputs with analytics and decision-support tools used as the basis for reorganization, consolidation and migration strategies.

Develop detailed user stories that can be used to create product specifications and architecture for each product and application

Active role on Cookie Consent Implementation for multiple websites country wise

Cognizant Technology Solutions as Associate

Feb 2018 to Feb 2020

Establish and own selection goals, identify and define metrics to show impact

Define analytical tools to draw insight from data to drive selection goals and process improvement

Maintain and govern integrations across Adobe tools including Dynamic Tag Management, Reports & Analytics (Omniture/Adobe Analytics)

Proactively identify opportunities for continuous improvement in site tagging, analytics and testing

Identify traffic trends, pathing issues and opportunities for improving site conversion rates

Act as administrator of web analytics tool, working internally to support and train others on the effective use of the tool

SkyQart Technologies as Digital Strategist

Jan 2015 to Nov 2017

Lead Vendor Management in all aspects including vendor selection, contract negotiation, invoice approvals, and optimizing vendor delivery and performance

1/22/2021

Perform in-depth analysis of information from multiple data sources (web analytics data as well as external data) and provide significant insights into factors impacting online results

Provide quick turnaround responses to ad hoc data queries

Produce daily, weekly, monthly, and quarterly reports relating to outcomes based on the data analysis for various audiences, including management and marketing

Ensure data accuracy by investigating data anomalies to determine if there are any issues, work with IT and Development teams to address issues, log issues to prevent the issue from reoccurring

Creating effective and holistic dashboards and presentations for senior leadership on digital marketing effectiveness Measuring the effectiveness of digital campaigns by leveraging A/B and/or multivariate testing to refine performance over time

Designing System Architecture of a Product based on Programmatic Media Buying

Webgen Infosystems as SEO Analyst

Aug 2013 to Jan 2015

- ? Performing basic search engine optimization (SEO) tasks
- ? Completed weekly reports, identified new business opportunities, and worked on the development and implementation of new business procedures and processes which significantly improved customer experience and satisfaction
- ? Improved web content and email campaigns ensuring that client's business standards were always met
- ? Manage product performance: usage, delivery etc.
- ? Assists with tracking & reporting of cost actuals to budget against marketing plans, campaigns and objectives

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from BPUT, Odisha in 2013

PG: in 0

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
HTML, CSS, BOOTSTRAP, JAVASCRIPT			
Python, Adobe Analytics, Google Analytics			
GTM, DTM, Adobe Launch			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Odiya	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time